<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-01T21:46:55-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">JVKrakowski</title><subtitle>Online resume of JV Krakowski</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Writing Content for Better Reading [UPDATED]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/content/2021/03/21/write-content-better-reading.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Content for Better Reading [UPDATED]" /><published>2021-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/content/2021/03/21/write-content-better-reading</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/content/2021/03/21/write-content-better-reading.html">&lt;p&gt;It takes four seconds for people to decide whether the content is worth reading. Everything from font and format to site design and layout will affect their decision. However, nothing makes readers click away faster than ill-written content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grammatical errors in any form are a turnoff, making the content writer seem less of an expert. Well-written content ensures that someone is intelligent. There are rough drafts and edits for a reason. Every content writer is encouraged to take that process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revisit content after a year and ask, “How can this be improved?” That is a healthy, professional attitude for content writers. It is also suitable for content rankings. It renews interest in the content and gives people reason to return to a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-tools-are-important&quot;&gt;Writing Tools are Important&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing Content for Better Reading was rewritten after a decade online. The original system that ranked it as quality content has changed. The readers presented with the content have changed. More writing tools are available to content writers, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing wrong with that, either. Writing tools exist to make writing quality content easier. Using them to critique and modify content is a good practice. It helps keep content readable, grammatically correct, and SEO compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all content is public-worthy after a decade, though, but that judgment is up to the content writer to make. Make sure content is worth reading, and then take it through the writing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-is-the-1-priority&quot;&gt;Content is the #1 priority&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People visit and revisit websites for content. It conveys information and guides a person through their online experience. Think of it as a website’s persuasive edge. Good, well-written content will persuade people to transition from visitor to customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content is an integral way people connect with a company online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoiding-skip-around&quot;&gt;Avoiding Skip Around&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A skip around is flitting from one place to another without comprehending anything. There is no real engagement, and people only nitpick what they need. These people are unlikely to visit again or find value in the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement is what companies need to rank and persuade. The more engagement occurs, the more valuable the content is. Here are a few tips to avoid skip around:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-it-short-and-direct&quot;&gt;Keep it short and direct.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write like the audience is in third grade. Keep content direct, and break everything into small, digestible portions. Avoid paginating content because only clickbait does that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus the content by cutting out unnecessary details. Concentrate only on essential points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it like this: Someone needs a tutorial about creating a menu with jQuery. Does that person care about the history of jQuery? Does it matter why jQuery was chosen instead of plain CSS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody cares about those details. Cut them out and continue writing what is important. Here are some other tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-bullet-headings&quot;&gt;Use bullet headings.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break up significant content with bullet headings. Each heading should highlight an important point. Much like this post is doing. Content is more readable that way. It helps people comprehend it better, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lists-are-great&quot;&gt;Lists are great.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists are like bullet headings; it is a fantastic way to relay large amounts of data in short bursts. Buzzfeed is known for viral blog posts like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;infographics-help-people-keep-information&quot;&gt;Infographics help people keep information.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infographics are beneficial visual aids. These images are attractive and condense information into a sharable format. It is effortless to share to Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;highlight-important-information&quot;&gt;Highlight important information.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If information needs to stand out, then highlight it someway. Using a different color — or bolding it out — makes it easier for people to see it. People pay attention to words or items on a page that seem visually different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-not-paginate-a-blog-post&quot;&gt;Do not paginate a blog post.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point is so crucial that we reiterated it. Paginating content is annoying. Most importantly, it is counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reader will skim headlines or visit the comment section to avoid reading the content. That is not encouraging engagement or comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existence of a feature does not mean that we need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;focus-on-a-topic-not-a-subject&quot;&gt;Focus on a topic, not a subject.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focused content is easy to digest, attractive, and reader-friendly. Writing focused content is like writing a recipe versus an entire cookbook. Some algorithms reward longer content, but readers may not. That does not mean it should be full of worthless details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;readers-vs-search-engines&quot;&gt;Readers vs. Search Engines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, search engines have changed how people write. If better traffic is the goal, the content has to meet specific criteria. Content that meets criteria receives more attention by receiving a higher rank. It weeds out poorly written content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search Engine Optimization (SEO) helps people gain better rankings. Unfortunately, that does not guarantee their content is well written or even current. A good rank means it met the criteria, not that a content writer is fantastic. The writing process helps with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is only part of the work, however. After publishing, the next step is promoting that content across social media. That is a new type of writing designed to hook a visitor in a few short sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing for social media has become a challenge all its own. Different platforms have different criteria to rank and deliver content. Understanding how their algorithms work is key to attracting readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting to visitors through writing is an essential part of business online. Good writing is easy to understand, appealing, and easy to access. While it is more work for content writers, the rewards can be lucrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a formula for content writing that works for their readers. What works for one content writer may not work for another. Doing a bit of research about readers will help form one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-write-content-better-reading-judia-krakowski/&quot;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J.V Krakowski</name></author><category term="reading" /><category term="content" /><summary type="html">It takes four seconds for people to decide whether the content is worth reading. Everything from font and format to site design and layout will affect their decision. However, nothing makes readers click away faster than ill-written content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking Back</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/01/22/looking-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking Back" /><published>2021-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/01/22/looking-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/01/22/looking-back.html">&lt;p&gt;Last night, I saw a photo on Facebook with a quote, “I know everything happens for a reason, but what the fuck?!” Nothing described 2020 better than that, if you ask me. Was there anyone that didn’t do something in excess for that year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the American Heart Association, alcohol sales were up 54%. I know quite a few people that helped keep that number up. As trapped extroverts, I understood that prolonged time alone was taxing for them. Personally speaking, I found it refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were things that I missed, even as introverted as I am. I wanted to eat at a restaurant and go to a movie. I wanted to socialize my baby (who had been born the previous year). I wanted to stop wearing a mask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have thalassemia, and I was on the high risk list. That didn’t leave me with much to do, honestly. I went back to college, but I couldn’t tell you when I started that. I struggled with my own mental health (non-quarantine related) and a host of other problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of it all, I was struggling to keep my business open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember when I said everyone did something in excess? Well, I exited 2020 pregnant with a second baby. Jonathan, my husband, and I wanted another baby, but I hadn’t planned on it happening so quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I came into 2021 pregnant, miserable, and looking for better things. I was happy that we were installing a new administration. I had a new, good paying job. I’ll be wrapping up my master’s degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a good year of positive progress. I understand that 2020 was hard on everyone, but I’m coming out of a 4-year hell haul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heart.org/en/news/2020/07/01/covid-19-pandemic-brings-new-concerns-about-excessive-drinking&quot;&gt;American Heart Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J.V Krakowski</name></author><category term="design" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">Last night, I saw a photo on Facebook with a quote, “I know everything happens for a reason, but what the fuck?!” Nothing described 2020 better than that, if you ask me. Was there anyone that didn’t do something in excess for that year? According to the American Heart Association, alcohol sales were up 54%. I know quite a few people that helped keep that number up. As trapped extroverts, I understood that prolonged time alone was taxing for them. Personally speaking, I found it refreshing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet Panda</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design/2020/11/07/meet-panda.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Panda" /><published>2020-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design/2020/11/07/meet-panda</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design/2020/11/07/meet-panda.html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a mascot, so I created a cute panda that I intend to plaster on merchandise that I’ll be selling. The designs are originals of mine, and I’m very proud of them. I’ll have an entire line of my (currently unnamed) panda in various scenes. This was at the suggestion of close friends and family that saw me doodling the character a few months back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to name my panda or choose a real gender, but those will be coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/baking-panda.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 200px; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proud-panda.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 200px; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/mockup-soldier.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 200px; height: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed the panda for merchandise to sell from my website. The website isn’t available right now, but it should be up soon. I’m hoping people will like it. I’m writing tutorials to accompany the simple repositories on Github, and I wanted to feature my panda to narrate it. It will showcase my diverse, unique skillset.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J.V Krakowski</name></author><category term="design" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">Everyone needs a mascot, so I created a cute panda that I intend to plaster on merchandise that I’ll be selling. The designs are originals of mine, and I’m very proud of them. I’ll have an entire line of my (currently unnamed) panda in various scenes. This was at the suggestion of close friends and family that saw me doodling the character a few months back. I have yet to name my panda or choose a real gender, but those will be coming soon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Scenes: Creating the Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web/2020/09/22/behind-scenes-creating-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Scenes: Creating the Website" /><published>2020-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web/2020/09/22/behind-scenes-creating-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web/2020/09/22/behind-scenes-creating-website.html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone likes knowing what happens behind the curtains. Knowing you’re in on a secret is an enticing feeling that most people take at first opportunity. It’s a sense of adventure that makes behind-the-scenes content interesting. I thought a little behind-the-scenes action would be a breath of fresh are for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I launched a personal website a few months ago. It was part of a graduation project for my masters degree. It needed to showcase our leadership abilities and professional skills. We could use either Wix or Wordpress to make it, per the assignment rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked to develop it myself and launch it on Github Pages. The professors gave me a go-ahead, and, now, here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a whole, I prefer minimalist designs that focus on content and users. It can be a bit underwhelming, though, so I chose somewhat of an in-between. The color palette and layout are my own creation. The background image, though, is a product of FreePik.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By my thinking, a personal website is like a digital resume. I modeled the website with a creative resume in mind. I looked at roughly a hundred similar sites to get a good feel for the premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to build the website on Jekyll, since it’s my latest favorite. Jekyll is a creation of Github’s co-founder, Tom Preston-Werner. It’s written in Ruby and uses Markdown, Liquid, HTML, and CSS to deliver a static site. It was quick and easy without the need for regular updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I can focus on writing content, working on assignments, and being a mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll makes it easy to create websites. It doesn’t showcase any kind of genius or skill. Since I haven’t used Github, I don’t have other projects to make up for that. I would’ve uploaded past projects, but I lost most of my work when my computer crashed a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, I didn’t bother storing my code on an online platform like Github. It wasn’t a lack of skill with Git or anything, but rather a lack of motivation to take that extra step to preserve my code. I felt uncomfortable leaving my code out there for anyone to rove through at will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very private with my work. I still am (to a degree). I’m working on passion projects to showcase what I can do. I’d like to get them all released before I shoot a list out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, check out Jekyll and Github when you have a moment. Both are awesome resources.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J.V Krakowski</name></author><category term="behind-the-scenes" /><category term="web" /><summary type="html">Everyone likes knowing what happens behind the curtains. Knowing you’re in on a secret is an enticing feeling that most people take at first opportunity. It’s a sense of adventure that makes behind-the-scenes content interesting. I thought a little behind-the-scenes action would be a breath of fresh are for everyone.</summary></entry></feed>